<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <channel><title>Blog</title> <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description. </description><link>https://whiteseeker.github.io/</link> <atom:link href="https://whiteseeker.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/> <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:01:09 +0000</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:01:09 +0000</lastBuildDate> <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator> <item><title>Monster Hotel</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Monster Hotel&lt;/em&gt; let you run your very own hotel for (cute) monsters. Some monsters like stinky room, others super cold room, some are super angry and just break everything in your hotel… And your goal is to please them all ! So more happy they are the more money they’ll give you when leaving.&lt;!--more--&gt; Moar money =&amp;gt; more rooms =&amp;gt; more monster =&amp;gt; &lt;em&gt;moar problems&lt;/em&gt;. It sounds a bit masochist but it’s a lot of fun !&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once more it’s a mobile game coming from &lt;a href="https://motion-twin.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Motion Twin&lt;/a&gt; (If you missed it, I already wrote about &lt;a href="/mobile/game/2015/08/09/uppercup-football.html"&gt;Uppercup Football&lt;/a&gt; from Motion Twin too). They again bring creativity in Monster Hotel: The gameplay is a new &lt;strong&gt;mix between reflexion/puzzle and builder/fallout shelter&lt;/strong&gt;. And they have a really polished game on many levels:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;The art style is just perfect: It’s cute but not too Kawaii, and it feel like you’re playing in someone’s weird imagination.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Again the gameplay: It not hard core, it’s easy at first but quickly become challenging.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;The monetisation: The game is &lt;strong&gt;free to install&lt;/strong&gt;, with in app purchase. It could be a bad thing but it isn’t. Ads tends to break your immersion, and these in-app-purchases are of 2 type: &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Long term items: Items that you purchase once and keep forever.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Short term boost. While I personnaly don’t like short term boost, I enjoy purchasing the long term items because it just feel paying for the full game.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Music ! It’s a &lt;strong&gt;really cool music&lt;/strong&gt; that get in your head. I just wish they add more music &amp;amp; variation!&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Features: &lt;strong&gt;Cloud save&lt;/strong&gt;, achievement, a bit of social/friends but not too much, oh and BTW the game is &lt;strong&gt;playable in your browser&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://monster-hotel.net/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Usually I finish with a word about the dev, but it’s already done in &lt;a href="/mobile/game/2015/08/09/uppercup-football.html"&gt;Uppercup Football&lt;/a&gt;. I won’t stop talking about them until they got the attention they deserve. It’s really rare to find a game studio bringing such creativity in mobile games.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 21:10:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/12/04/monster-hotel.html</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/12/04/monster-hotel.html</guid> <category>mobile</category> <category>game</category> </item> <item><title>Thug Racer</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thug Racer&lt;/em&gt; bring &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Out_Run" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Out Run&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on mobile! Driving a sport car, escaping the cops, time limit … One really cool indie game with retro graphics!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As many good game it’s easy to learn and hard to master. Super simple controls: turn left, turn right and brake. An easy goal: complete 5 stages as quickly as possible. But completing that goal require a lot of practise and skills to avoid other cars, escape police patrols and avoid crashing in the walls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monetisation is really good: you can play the game in arcade mode (the main one) for free,with some ads from time to time at the end of a run. You can also do a one time purchase to get a new golden skin on your car, get access to the endless mode, remove the ads, and also help an indie!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thug Racer is made by &lt;a href="http://www.supercookie.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;Super Coockie Games&lt;/a&gt;, two indie game developers from London: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/spectrumzx128k"&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MonsterofCookie" target="_blank"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 20:48:53 +0100</pubDate><link>https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/10/01/thug-racer.html</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/10/01/thug-racer.html</guid> <category>mobile</category> <category>game</category> </item> <item><title>Cards and Castles</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cards and Castles&lt;/em&gt; is a fresh mix of &lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;rading &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;ard &lt;strong&gt;G&lt;/strong&gt;ame &amp;amp; turn-based strategy game. Lately I haven’t been a fan of all the clones of Magic the Gathering that popped up lately on mobile apart from Hearthstone! But Cards and Castles get me intrigued, and pleasantly surprised.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In C&amp;amp;C you play your cards to create units on a battlefield, or influence them with buff and debuff. Unlike most TCG game, the battlefield is a grid with lots of cells (5*9). Consequently choosing your deck is only one part of the strategy: using your units properly on the battlefield is at least as important. You’ll have to position them, calculate range etc, guess the opponent next move &amp;amp; cards, prepare for area damage, etc. The game has 5 different factions: Vikings, Crusaders, Pirates, Warlocks and Ninjas. Each deck can mix together 2 factions, or just use one faction, as you prefer. The difference between factions and the variety of cards available give you a lot of freedom to create synergy in your deck, and offer a deep gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;C&amp;amp;C has a single player mode, but, as for most TCG, all the fun really start when you compete against real players. You’ll have quests, monthly reward for ranked game (custom skin …). Game is really well balanced and devs are very close from the community, listening to feedback and reacting very quickly. The game also have frequent update with new content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monetisation is done through pack of cards you can either purchase with real money or with the in game virtual currency (roughly one pack of card every 3-4 multiplayer game depending on quest and victory ratio (^_^) ). However to get the most rare cards you’ll be likely to spend money, and the cards you get are random, with no way to exchange between players. Unlike hearthstone you can’t craft the specific card you need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This mobile game is made by &lt;a href="http://www.cardsandcastles.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Bit Mass&lt;/a&gt;, an indie studio of 5 game developers based in San Diego. Oh and BTW the game is cross platform Android, iOS and PC (&lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/360730/" target="_blank"&gt;steam&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 11:27:11 +0100</pubDate><link>https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/09/28/cards-and-castles.html</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/09/28/cards-and-castles.html</guid> <category>mobile</category> <category>game</category> </item> <item><title>Uppercup Football</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uppercup Football&lt;/em&gt; is an intense &lt;strong&gt;fantasy soccer-ball&lt;/strong&gt; mobile game with crazy rules. Believe me, I’m not usually a fan of soccer-ball and even less in a video game, but Uppercup Football add a ton of fun into it !&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First it has a super easy control system, &lt;strong&gt;one handed&lt;/strong&gt;, in turn by turn, really perfect for mobile. Second you have some crazy rules, changing each match, like: Rugby balls, electroballs, trees or even mines on the field, etc. Finally there is about 100 levels, all different, with more and more challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can perceive the amount of time and effort spent in polishing the game, the menus and gameplay. The &lt;strong&gt;art and animations are great&lt;/strong&gt;, but I’ll let you judge by yourself as the game is &lt;strong&gt;free to install&lt;/strong&gt; with a one time in app purchase to unlock the full version (restorable on any device). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://motion-twin.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Motion Twin&lt;/a&gt; is the french studio behind Uppercup Football. Motion has a few extraordinary component:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every employee has the same share of the company&lt;/strong&gt;. That mean the same salary, same power of decision, same responsibility.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;They have their own open source programming language called &lt;a href="http://haxe.org/" target="_blank"&gt;HaXe&lt;/a&gt;. It can be compiled into C++, Action Script of Javascript and all their games are made with HaXe.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;They made a &lt;strong&gt;ton of great web browser games&lt;/strong&gt; with a unique gameplay that you’ve &lt;strong&gt;NEVER&lt;/strong&gt; seen anywhere else. If I had to pick one: &lt;a href="http://mush.twinoid.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Mush&lt;/a&gt;, but there are more, a lot more.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;11 frogs. Errrr employees I mean (^_^) &lt;strong&gt;Go try uppercup football!&lt;/strong&gt; You have no excuse it’s free to install!&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; </description> <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 07:21:03 +0100</pubDate><link>https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/08/09/uppercup-football.html</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/08/09/uppercup-football.html</guid> <category>mobile</category> <category>game</category> </item> <item><title>Sorcery</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Today let’s check &lt;em&gt;Sorcery&lt;/em&gt;. Do you know the “books where you are the Hero”? If you liked these books as much as me, you’ll love Sorcery, and if you don’t know them but like Fantastic books, you should really try it!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After choosing your character you’ll start a captivating adventure, full of mystery, and you’ll decide every actions of your hero. When you played The Witcher or Mass Effect you barely have 5-7 meaningful choices to make during one game. In Sorcery you have at least 100 of them, leading to different adventures, different difficulties, different stories to discover. You’ll fight monster with a unique combat system, collect and use items in your inventory, and even cast magic !&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you like Sorcery 1, you’ll be able to pursuit the same adventure with Sorcery 2 and 3 where you can get your progress from the previous opus through a simple “code save” you get at the end of each game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sky is not 100% blue, the music could be better, the “game” also miss achievements to push you to explorer different path of the story, and cloud saving would have saved you from keeping note, somewhere, the code you get at the end of the story (And probably loosing it).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This mobile game is made by &lt;a href="http://www.inklestudios.com/" target="_blank"&gt;inkle&lt;/a&gt;, a studio founded in 2011 by 2 game developers in the UK. As game dev I have to mention &lt;a href="http://www.inklestudios.com/inklewriter/" target="_blank"&gt;Inklewriter&lt;/a&gt;, the tool behind Sorcery and The Banner Saga, designed to help you publish high quality interactive stories. Inklewriter is free (But I haven’t found the license). It’s a great tool to create this kind of book experience but also when creating cut scenes, &lt;a href="http://writer.inklestudios.com/" target="_blank"&gt;try it online&lt;/a&gt;! Sorcery is premium so no iaps, no ads, no bad surprises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="store_badges"&gt;Sorcery 1: &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.inkle.sorcery1" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/play_badge.png" alt="" title="Get it on Google Play" class="play_badge" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sorcery!/id627879091" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/apple_badge.svg" alt="" title="Download on the App Store" class="apple_badge" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="store_badges"&gt;Sorcery 2: &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.inkle.sorcery2" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/play_badge.png" alt="" title="Get it on Google Play" class="play_badge" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sorcery!-2/id627880433" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/apple_badge.svg" alt="" title="Download on the App Store" class="apple_badge" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="store_badges"&gt;Sorcery 3: &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.inkle.sorcery3" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/play_badge.png" alt="" title="Get it on Google Play" class="play_badge" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/app/sorcery!-3/id978352903" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/apple_badge.svg" alt="" title="Download on the App Store" class="apple_badge" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 03:36:51 +0100</pubDate><link>https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/07/30/sorcery.html</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/07/30/sorcery.html</guid> <category>mobile</category> <category>game</category> </item> <item><title>Rymdkapsel</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rymdkapsel&lt;/em&gt; took the essence realtime strategy (RTS) games and released it in a unique and pure experience.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you know about RTS you can hardly imagine be playing one on mobile given the amount of actions you have to do every seconds. Well Rymdkapsel succeed surprisingly well at removing the low level management to let you handle only the high level decisions. You decide the layout of your space station, the amount of minions in each kind of “job”, and then watch them working, adjusting your orders and adding new ones on the fly. You build the layout of your station by assembling rooms with different purpose. Each of this room have the shape of a tetris block which make it increasingly difficult to build an optimal station.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the gameplay, the art style is minimalist. It is relaxing and the design help you focus on what matters: taking decisions quickly, and reading easily what is happening in your station. Regarding the lenght of the game, Rymdkapsel offer 3 different modes: the normal mode, a harder mode called “Plus” and a “Zen” mode without enemies where you just play at your own pace. It also offer some achievements, and a leaderboard to compete for the longest resistance time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://grapefrukt.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Grapefrukt Games&lt;/a&gt; is the Sweden studio behind this mobile game. It consist of exactly one guy: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/grapefrukt/" target="_blank"&gt;Martin Jonasson&lt;/a&gt;. Finally Rymdkapsel is a premium title, so as usually, no bad surprise: no ads, no in app purchase, no hidden cost !&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 15:28:45 +0100</pubDate><link>https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/07/21/rymdkapsel.html</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/07/21/rymdkapsel.html</guid> <category>mobile</category> <category>game</category> </item> <item><title>Tiny Guardians</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tiny Guardians&lt;/em&gt; is a surprising strategy game where your role is to protect one enchantress, Lunalie, as she journeys in search of the Sorceress.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking some elements of tower defense gameplay, it twist them in a very refreshing way. Instead of protecting a fix point, as in a classic tower defense game, you protect Lunalie as she slowly travel through the map. And instead of building tower you choose the heroes that will protect her. You can choose from 12 different classes of heroes: knight, archer, cleric, assassins, etc. Each heroes has 4 upgrade, giving you plenty of different strategy to finish each level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gorgeous art style transport you across 14 different levels having a Story and Challenge Mode, each with three difficulties. Collecting every achievements require quite a lot of investment and will provide you with hours of gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tiny Guardians is a paymium title, it means that you pay to purchase the game and then the game offer some optional in-app-purchases. It may sound bad but actually these in-app-purchases are not at all necessary to completely finish the game in a reasonable amount of time. They are mostly there to unlock different esthetic outfits for each hero. So be reassured, you’ll not need to spend any additional money after purchasing the game. This mobile game was made by &lt;a href="http://kurechii.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Kurechii&lt;/a&gt;, a Malaysian independent game studio founded in 2009, and now employ 4 persons. &lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 05:41:17 +0100</pubDate><link>https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/07/18/tiny-guardians.html</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/07/18/tiny-guardians.html</guid> <category>mobile</category> <category>game</category> </item> <item><title>Haunt the house: Terrortown</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Haunt the house: Terrortown&lt;/em&gt; you play a mischievous ghost and scare people by possessing object, moving them around, making scary sounds or even spooking dinosaurs!&lt;!--more--&gt; You like the tranquility of your house and they dare to come and disturb you! As they start freaking out, running away, their fear make you even more powerful, and you’ll eventually make them flee the house and leave you alone!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The art style is really beautiful, funny and child friendly. Each animations create a marvelous atmosphere where you want to explore every objects, discover what you can do with them, and see the reaction on your “guests”. You can play at your own peace or compete for the first place in the leaderboard! There are also many achievements that help you discover every possibilities offered by the game if you want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This mobile game was made by &lt;a href="http://sfbgames.com/" target="_blank"&gt;SFB Games&lt;/a&gt;, a British independent game studio, founded by two brothers, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sfbtom" target="_blank"&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SFBDim" target="_blank"&gt;Adam&lt;/a&gt; Vian, who have been making games together since 2003. As Haunt the house is a premium title, you’ll have no bad surprise after the initial purchase: no ads, no in-app-purchase.&lt;/p&gt; </description> <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 22:44:13 +0100</pubDate><link>https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/07/15/haunt-the-house.html</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://whiteseeker.github.io/mobile/game/2015/07/15/haunt-the-house.html</guid> <category>mobile</category> <category>game</category> </item> </channel> </rss>